A Guide to the John S. and James L. Knight Foundation records, Knight Memorial Education Fund, RG 10 FA1804
Rockefeller Archive Center
John S. and James L. Knight Foundation records, Knight Memorial Education Fund, RG 10
1940-1987
Rockefeller Archive Center
John S. and James L. Knight Foundation
FA1804
1.52 Cubic Feet 4 letter document boxes
Biographical / Historical
The Knight Memorial Education Fund, also referred to as the C.L. Knight Memorial Education Fund was established in 1940 by John S. Knight in honor of his father, Charles L. Knight. The Fund's primary purpose was to give out college loans to students in the Akron, Ohio area for those studying medicine, journalism, and education. The loans provided by the Fund were expected to be repaid when the student was able to do so. The Knight Memorial Education Fund eventually turned into the Journalism and Education programs of the Knight Foundation.
Scope and Contents
Record Group 10 contains the records of the Knight Memorial Education Fund. Included are: the Scholarship/Loan Agreement, information for applicants, fund background information, award lists (1940-1942), newspaper clippings about the loan recipients (1940-1952), correspondence from John S. and James L. Knight, C.C. Gibson and Ben Maidenburg about grantees (1955-1985) repayments, and student loan files. The student files contain correspondence, photographs, clippings, and memos.
Arrangement
As received.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Student records less than 75 years old are restricted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Student loan funds
- Scholarship/Loan Agreement, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Information for applicants, 1940-1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Background information on the fund, award lists.
- News clippings, 1940-1952 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
- Grants to Students, 1950-1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  General
  Knight File Number - 1540
  List of grants to students, 1950-1959, from the C.L. Knight Memorial Education Fund.
- Grant Status Reports, 1959 July 14-1967 March 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Knight File Number - 1541
  Grant status reports from the C.L. Knight Memorial Education Fund, including repayment schedules for each grantee.
- Grantees - Correspondence with and about, 1955-1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Correspondents: James L. Knight, C. C. Gibson, John S. Knight, and Ben Maidenburg.
- Student Loan Files, 1950-1987; 1
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted – Student Records – Open in 2062.
  - Arnold, Horace Leroy, Jr., 1966-1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Auburn, Richard, 1958-1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Aylward, Constance Mary, 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bajcsa, Andras, 1960-1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Biddinger, John E., 1962-1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bonstelle, Charles, 1964-1975 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Brown, Beverly (Mrs. James P. Levy), 1961-1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Brown, Robert H., 1964-1973 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Brubaker, Martha, 1965-1974 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Burton, Robert L., 1952-1977 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Camp, Gregory Burnham, 1960-1974 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Capotosto, Richard, 1960-1972 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Conner, Constance, 1959-1982 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Cook, Albert, 1963-1987 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Curry, Jane, 1960-1973 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Denning, Richard, 1965-1985 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Dimascio, Ramon S., 1950-1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Dougherty, Michael, 1959-1975 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Evans, Thomas, 1962-1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Federman, Jerold Bruce, 1958-1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Fink, David, 1961-1981 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - France, Kathleen Ann, 1965-1974 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Gabel, Roberta Ann, 1959-1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Garrett, Dorothy, 1966-1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Glassner, E. Donald, 1960-1977 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Grow, James, 1963-1980 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Haas, William S., 1961-1971 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Hardin, Michael A., 1962-1968 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Harter, Thomas C., 1962-1972 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Heller, Ronald J., 1959-1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Horner, Tom S., 1957 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Jenkins, Lyle, 1964-1982 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Johnson, Jim L., 1960-1982 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Knox, David W., 1963-1977 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Kodish, Martin E., 1965-1987 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Kopelson, Marvin, 1959-1977 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Lezowitz, Robert I, 1961-1978 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Lin, Dinah Rita, 1960-1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Mallo, Lana M., 1963-1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - McNair, Clarence, 1960-1978 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Monahan, James S., 1960-1976 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - McDermott, Dennis M., 1965-1982 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Neff, John C., 1959-1974 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Oblinger, James L., 1963-1977 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Phillips, Sandra Jo, 1965-1980 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Pratt, Charles E., 1959-1982 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Riffle, James, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Robb, Steven, 1962-1986 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Sandlin, Charles R. Jr, 1966-1982 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Sauer, James R., 1959-1974 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Schaal, Stephen F., 1962-1982 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Scheffer, Robert B., 1965-1970 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Schenz, Timothy, 1964-1978 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Sherman, Sandra J., 1962-1982 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Stagner, Cecily O, 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Steinkerchner, Raymond, 1959-1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Stopher, Robert H. Jr., 1958-1969 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Stuver, Susan K (Murray), 1965-1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Sutter, Leonette Rowe, 1960-1978 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Terry, Roger Lee, 1966-1983 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Thomas, David P., 1961-1973 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Tynan, Lawrence K., 1963-1972 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Walsh, Patrick C., 1960-1982 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Waltz, Edward Lee, 1965-1978 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Williams, Herminia Jarpa, 1959-1963 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Williams, Jo Ellen, 1960-1983 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Williamson, Martha, 1959-1967 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Winder, Denis J., 1964-1981 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Wise, Perry M., 1961-1985 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Woodlee, James E., 1964-1978 (Box 4, Folder 17)